Ragav Venkatesan

This document has embedded web-links and is made for a computer viewing only. Click here for a printable version.

CONTACT Email: ragav.venkatesan@gmail.com

Links LinkedIn Homepage Google Scholar GitHub Amazon Books

Summary

Senior Software Engineer with experience in building enterprise-level, cost-efficient distributed machine learning and computer vision platforms and a breadth of research areas spanning MLops, multiple-instance learning, object detection, domain adaptation video-enhancement and neural network compression.

Professional Experience (E1) Nvidia AI

(N1) Senior Software Engineer - Nvidia Maxine AI Platform

August 2021 – Present

(E2) Amazon

(A1) Applied Scientist - Amazon Alexa AI

November 2019 - August 2021

(A2) Applied Scientist - Amazon Web Services, AI Labs

May 2019 - November 2019

(A3) Research Scientist - Amazon Web Services, Sagemaker

November 2017 - May 2019

Publicly Available Artifacts:

• Open Source: Amazon SageMaker Reinforcement Learning.

• Launch Announcement: Amazon SageMaker Object Detection Algorithms.

• Launch Announcement: Amazon SageMaker Semantic Segmentation Algorithms.

• Launch Announcement: Bring your own Tensorflow and MXNet models to SageMaker.

• Open Source: Neural Network Compression using AWS SageMaker RL.

(E3) Research Assistant - Arizona State University.

August 2011 – October 2017

• The Diabetic Retinopathy project

Funding Agency: National Institutes of Health.

• The MIDAS project

Funding Agency: National Science Foundation.

(E4) Researcher Intern - Intel

December 2013 – August 2014

• Built vehicle and lane detection for automated driver assistance systems applications.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy - Computer Science

October 2017

Advisor: Professor Baoxin Li

Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, USA

Master of Science - Electrical Engineering

August 2012

Advisor: Professor David Frakes

Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, USA

 ${\bf Bachelor\ of\ Engineering}$ - Electronics and Communication Engineering

June 2010

Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Воокѕ

(B1) Ragav Venkatesan, Baoxin Li, "Convolutional Neural Networks in Visual Computing: A Concise Guide", CRC Press, a Tyler & Francis company, 2017.

Ragav Venkatesan, Baoxin Li, "卷积神经网络与视觉计算", 机械工业出版社, 2019.

BOOK CHAPTERS (Bc1) Xiang Xu, Xiong Zhou, **Ragav Venkatesan**, Gurumurthy Swaminathan, Orchid Majumdar, "

d-SNE: Domain Adaptation using Stochastic Neighborhood Embedding." in Domain Adaptation in Computer Vision With Deep Learning, edited by Hemanth Venkateswara, Sethuraman Panchanathan, in Springer Nature, 2020.

(Bc2) Parag Chandakkar, **Ragav Venkatesan**, Baoxin Li, "Feature Extraction and Learning for Visual Data" in "Feature Engineering for Machine Learning and Data Analytics, CRC Press, a Tyler & Francis company, 2017.

SELECTED
PEER-REVIEWED
CONFERENCES

- (C1) Ansel MacLaughlin, Jwala Dhamala, Anoop Kumar, Sriram Venkatapathy, Ragav Venkatesan, Rahul Gupta, "Evaluating the Effectiveness of Efficient Neural Architecture Search for Sentence-Pair Tasks.", in Workshop on Insights from Negative Results in NLP at the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020. [ORAL]
- (C2) Xiang Xu, Xiong Zhou, **Ragav Venkatesan**, Gurumurthy Swaminathan, Orchid Majumdar "d-SNE: Domain Adaptation using Stochastic Neighborhood Embedding.", in IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), Long Beach, California, USA, 2019. [ORAL]
- (C3) Ragav Venkatesan, Jaya Vijetha Gattupalli, Baoxin Li, "On the generality of neural image features.", in IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), Phoenix, Arizona, USA, 2016. [ORAL]
- (C4) Ragav Venkatesan, Parag Shridhar Chandakkar, Baoxin Li, "Simpler non-parametric methods provide as good or better results to multiple-instance learning.", in *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, Santiago, Chile 2015. [Spotlight]
- (C5) Ragav Venkatesan, Parag Shridhar Chandakkar, Baoxin Li, "Video-Based Self-Positioning for Intelligent Transport Systems Applications", in the Tenth International Symposium on Visual Computing (ISVC), Las Vegas, Nevada, USA, 2015. [ORAL]
- (C6) Ragav Venkatesan, Christine Zwart, David Frakes, Baoxin Li, "Perception-Inspired Spatio-Temporal Video Deinterlacing", in the Eighth International Workshop on Video Processing and Quality Metrics for Consumer Electronics (VPQM), Tempe, Arizona, USA, 2014. [ORAL]
- (C7) Parag Shridhar Chandakkar*, Ragav Venkatesan*, Baoxin Li, Helen Li, "Retrieving clinically relevant diabetic retinopathy images using a multi-class multiple-instance framework", in proceedings of SPIE conference on Medical Imaging, International Society of Opticals and Photonics, Orlando, Florida, USA, 2013. [ORAL]
- (C8) Ragav Venkatesan*, Parag Shridhar Chandakkar*, Baoxin Li, Helen Li, "Classification of Diabetic Retinopathy Images Using Multi-Class Multiple-Instance Learning Based on Color Correlogram Features", in Proceedings of International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society 2012 (EMBC'12), San Diego, California, USA, 2012. [Poster]
- (C9) Ragav Venkatesan*, Parag Shridhar Chandakkar*, Baoxin Li, Helen Li, "Clinically Relevant Diabetic Retinopathy Image Retrieval Using a Multi-Class Multiple Instance Framework", in proceedings of ACM conference on Bio-informatics, Computational Biology and Biomedicine (ACM-BCB'12). Orlando, Florida 2012. [ORAL]
- (C10) Ragav Venkatesan, Christine Zwart, David Frakes, "Video Deinterlacing with Control Grid Interpolation Frameworks", in Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), Orlando, Florida, USA, 2012. [Poster]
 * Equal contribution from authors.

SELECTED
PEER-REVIEWED
JOURNALS

- (J1) Parag Shridhar Chandakkar, Ragav Venkatesan, Baoxin Li, "MIRank-KNN: Multiple Instance Retrieval of Clinically-Relevant Diabetic Retinopathy Image", in SPIE Journal of Medical Imaging, 2017.
- (J2) Ragav Venkatesan, Christine Zwart, David Frakes, Baoxin Li" Spatio-temporal Video Deinterlacing using Control Grid Interpolation", in SPIE Journal of Electronic Imaging, 24(2), 023022. 2015.
- (J3) Christine Zwart, Ragav Venkatesan, David Frakes, "Decomposed Multidimensional Control Grid Interpolation for Common Interpolation-Based Image Processing Applications in Consumer Electronics", in SPIE Journal of Electronic Imaging, vol. 24, no.4, pp.43012-1 to 43012-12. 2012.

SELECTED ARXIV AND LONGFORM

- (A1) Ragav Venkatesan, Gurumurthy Swaminathan, Xiong Zhou, Anna Luo, "Out-of-the-box channel pruned networks.", arXiv: 2004.14584 2020.
- (A2) Ragav Venkatesan, Hemanth Venkateshwara, Sethuraman Panchanathan, Baoxin Li., "A strategy for an uncompromising incremental learner.", arXiv: 1705.00744 2017.
- (A3) Ragav Venkatesan, Vijetha Gattupalli, Baoxin Li., "Neural Dataset Generality.", arXiv: 1605.04369 2016.
- (A4) Ragav Venkatesan, Baoxin Li., "Diving deeper into mentee networks.", arXiv: 1604.08220
- (A5) Lydia Manikonda, Ragav Venkatesan, Subbarao Kambhampati, and Baoxin Li., "Evolution of fashion brands on Twitter and Instagram.", arXiv: 1512.01174 2015.

DISSERTATION

- (R1) Doctoral dissertation Novel image features and learning techniques.
- October 2017
- (R2) Masters thesis Video Deinterlacing using Control Grid Interpolation Frameworks. August 2012
- (R3) Undergraduate thesis A comparative study of detection of faults and estimation of distance to faults on wired communication channels, using TDR and FDR techniques. May 2010

Issued Patents

- (P1) Ragav Venkatesan, Gurumurthy Swaminathan, Xiong Zhou, Anna Luo, Vineet Khare "Reinforcement learning for training compression policies for machine learning models." US11501173B1
- (P2) Ragav Venkatesan, Gurumurthy Swaminathan, "Domain mapping for privacy preservation." US10567334B1

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- (T1) Instructor Amazon Machine Learning University. Convolutional Neural Networks (2018 - 2019)
- (T2) Instructor Arizona State University. CSE 591: Introduction to deep learning for visual computing (January - May 2017)
- (T3) Co-instructor Arizona State University. CSE 509: Digital Video Processing (August 2015 - December 2015)
- (T4) Teaching Assistant Arizona State University.
 - CSE 575: Statistical Machine Learning
 - Dr. Jingrui He (January 2015 May 2015)
 - CSE 569: Fundamentals of Statistical Learning
 - Dr. Baoxin Li (August 2014 December 2014 and August 2016 December 2016)
 - CSE 509: Digital Video Processing
 - Dr. David Claveau (August 2012 December 2012)
 - Dr. Hari Sundaram (August 2013 December 2013)
 - CSE 424, 485 and 486: Capstone Projects (January 2013 May 2013)
- (T5) Guest Lectures Arizona State University.

Duties in this position involve providing specific lectures in courses on invitation.

- CSE 569: Hidden Markov Models (September 2017)
- CSE 569: Neural Networks (October November 2017)

References

Will be provided on request.